- Madam
Speaker 1: President, I return to the floor of the Senate again today to ask that this body take immediate action, action
needed
Speaker 2: to address our nation's massive baby formula shortage. For months, American moms and dads have been
Speaker 3: scouring supermarkets and drugstores looking for baby formula. Anxiety-ridden parents are frantically checking online stores and pleading with family and friends, trying to figure out how to
ship
Speaker 4: purchase and otherwise procure baby formula. Still, some families must hospitalize their babies because they can't find
Speaker 5: formula. Yes, they're hospitalizing
Speaker 6: them for that reason alone. Inexcusably, the crisis has only gotten worse. In May alone, reports show that
Speaker 3: the out-of-stock rate jumped from 43% to a staggering 73% nationally.
In
Speaker 3: Utah, my state, the state with the largest families, the most children per capita, and the highest birth rate in the
Speaker 7: nation, reports show that out-of-stock rate to be as high as 88.9%. Desperate parents are now resorting to places like Facebook
Speaker 4: Marketplace, buying from unknown sellers
at
Speaker 8: exorbitant markups. The
failure of
Speaker 8: the Biden
Speaker 3: administration's photo op policy has not so much as put a dent
Speaker 3: even a tiny dent in this problem. Now, initially, the White House said that parents
Speaker 8: should, quote, "Ask your pediatrician who may have formula samples or possible alternatives," as if that were somehow a solution. This hollow non-response was embarrassing enough, but tragically, the administration's response has
Speaker 3: not improved with time in the time that's passed since that statement was made.
When
Speaker 3: the question came up again, the White House press secretary spent nearly 20 seconds flipping through a binder
Speaker 9: only to respond with, "I don't have anything new."
Speaker 4: Madam President, that response is simply unacceptable. It's unacceptable for the American people generally and especially
Speaker 2: for those families dealing with this inexplicably, needlessly prolonged crisis.
By
Speaker 2: failing to act, we're leaving parents in an unimaginable situation
during one
Speaker 2: of the most stressful and impactful
Speaker 8: times of life. Worse, they've received no discernible answers from their elected officials. The White House's website lays the blame solely on Abbott's plant closure in Michigan, quote, due to safety concerns from the FDA. But
this is a
Speaker 8: very limited situation.
Speaker 8: narrow line of thinking. The FDA regularly recalls other food products, but none of those recalls happens to result in
Speaker 2: shortages of this magnitude or this significance with such weighty consequences on the youngest of Americans. Look, it doesn't have to be this way. There are a lot of
Speaker 4: weighty problems that we address in the United States Senate that are seemingly unsolvable, intractable, or at least very, very difficult to solve.
Speaker 4: because they involve things that very often are beyond our ability to control. This is not one of those problems. This is within our grasp, it's within our control. In fact, government is the problem. Government caused it, and by turning certain levers,
Speaker 3: government can relieve this problem and do so in a very short period of time. This suffering is unnecessarily being prolonged by the government
itself.
So the
Speaker 3: Senate can help these families, these American families struggling with this crisis by immediately passing my bill called the Formula Act. This bill responds to the crisis in three simple ways to help solve the crisis at hand and feed American babies. First, my bill would suspend tariff collection on currently allowed formula imports. We tax imported formula at a rate of at least 17.5%.
Speaker 1: upon entering the United States. It can roughly double to about 35%, depending on the circumstances of the shipment. We can help ease the skyrocketing
Speaker 3: prices and encourage companies to import as much baby formula as possible, or as much as demand within the market requires, by simply suspending, for a period of six months, this tariff collection.
Speaker 3: Look, the
Speaker 4: administration has acknowledged there are appropriate times to suspend the collection of certain taxes. For example, it's currently proposing suspending the gasoline tax for a period of three
Speaker 8: months. Surely it's
not the Biden
Speaker 8: White House's position that gasoline is more important than feeding infants.
Speaker 3: Second, my bill would temporarily allow formula imports from several safe countries, like those in Europe.
This would
Speaker 3: enable us to access plentiful formula supplies from abroad and to meet our current needs with that. Now, allowing these imports is not gonna endanger American babies. The manufacturing plants in
question
Speaker 9: are already approved and are already regulated by their home countries, and the only plants operate in countries
Speaker 9: and subject to authorities that are comparable to those imposed by our own Food and Drug Administration. These are countries from
Speaker 3: which we already import pharmaceutical
products.
Speaker 8: The fact is that parents have already begun taking matters into their own hands, often with dire consequences. We're hearing
Speaker 3: reports of parents resorting to online homemade recipes.
for
Speaker 3: formula that they then feed to their infants.
Speaker 8: Infant hospitalizations due to malnutrition or are correspondingly increasing is a direct
Speaker 2: result of these activities and the shortages from
Speaker 4: which they stem.
Doctors have
Speaker 4: voiced their concerns that homemade formulas can lead to liver and kidney issues and in some cases, even heart failure. Some families have tried diluting the formula that they are able to access with more
water.
a
Speaker 4: tactic that health experts warn can lead to brain swelling and organ failure.
Speaker 9: Some doctors refer to this shortage as "the worst crisis they've experienced in their
Speaker 3: careers." They have to place dehydrated children on IV fluids, which isn't, of course, a long-term
Speaker 4: solution. It's an acute and dire response to a life-threatening emergency brought about through an artificial government constraint on
the market.
These
Speaker 3: short-term consequences are scary enough. They're scary enough for the moms and dads to say nothing of the horrors the children, the infants experience in the process. We still don't know what the long-term effects of these might be to the babies.
Those worried
Speaker 3: about the
Speaker 4: formula quality may find solace in the fact that my bill retains the FDA's authority to recall foreign formulas in the very unlikely event
Speaker 4: that these safety issues arise. Remember,
these are
Speaker 4: formulas produced
Speaker 9: in facilities in countries from which we already import pharmaceutical products based on our
Speaker 1: country's trust and confidence that their safety and quality standards are as secure as, if not more stringent than,
Speaker 3: our own.
Speaker 3: Additionally, my bill only calls for importing formula that's lawfully marketed and approved in select foreign countries. Again, private citizens are already doing this. The law already allows the personal importation of baby formula, meaning somebody can jump online and order it on their own. And parents are voluntarily choosing to do so because they've done the research
Speaker 4: and they trust that it's safe for their baby. They understand, as we do,
Speaker 4: that babies in France, in Switzerland, and in the United Kingdom are not different than babies in the United States of America. A formula that works for them, that's safe and healthy for them,
Speaker 3: that has proven safe and healthy and effective for them for many, many decades is also going to work with respect to American babies. My bill would just make this
Speaker 4: easier
and
Speaker 4: more affordable for parents. You see, because to be one of those parents, you've got to have a degree of sophistication to know what you're looking for. Most people aren't really aware of the fact that they could jump online and order this. Secondly, it's really expensive to do it. They can't buy in bulk, and it requires extra
Speaker 3: shipping and handling costs that makes this prohibitively expensive for many people, even the lucky ones, who become aware that it's even an option.
So my
Speaker 3: bill isn't making something legal that's currently illegal in that respect. It's
Speaker 4: simply making it more affordable. It's making it so that we no longer limit access to these foreign formulas, foreign top-quality formulas from places like France and Switzerland and the United Kingdom. They'll be
Speaker 3: available to poor middle-class families and not just the wealthy. Finally, my bill would allow WIC program recipients to buy whatever brand of formula is available with WIC vouchers.
My
Speaker 3: bill will allow these parents to buy from available stock and feed
Speaker 2: their children and guarantees greater flexibility. You see, the existing formula crisis has been exacerbated by virtue of the fact that the WIC beneficiaries are given a voucher. Very often, that voucher limits
Speaker 4: them to procuring only that brand of formula specified on the voucher itself, which in many instances might be out of stock.
this
Speaker 4: would eliminate that problem.
Madam
Speaker 10: President, keeping American infants fed should be one of the least controversial
Speaker 2: proposals imaginable, especially because this is something that can be done easily. We can bring about almost immediate relief
to these
Speaker 2: American parents, and especially to their babies, just by not causing the problem anymore,
Speaker 4: or at least waiting for a few months before causing this problem
again.
In the
Speaker 4: meantime, the hope and the expectation is that the American formula industry can retool, revamp and get back in the practice of producing in sufficient quantities that they'll be able to meet with demand, but we need six months in order to
do that.
Speaker 4: American babies are going
Speaker 9: hungry, and the federal
Speaker 3: government is the problem. The federal government is causing these babies to starve and otherwise suffer.
My
Speaker 3: Formula Act will help solve the formula
Speaker 1: crisis and ensure that American babies do not go unfed. Look, there is a reason why we see this crisis here, but not in any of our
Speaker 3: neighbor countries, not in any of our peer countries. No, the crisis exists here because this is a feature of U.S. law. We can fix this problem. We can help solve this crisis today. We can make sure American babies' cries
Speaker 8: do not go unanswered. We can and must
Speaker 8: "Pass my formula act." And so, Madam President, as if in legislative session,
Speaker 11: I ask unanimous consent that the Senate proceed to the immediate consideration of calendar number 372-S-4261. That the bill be considered read a third time
Speaker 12 (lower-pitched voice): and passed, and that the motion to reconsider be considered made and laid upon the table.
Speaker 13: - Is there objection?
Speaker 12 (lower-pitched voice): - Madam President.
Speaker 13: - The Senator from Pennsylvania.
Speaker 14 (lower-pitched voice): - Madam President.
Speaker 14 (lower-pitched voice): I rise to object to the senator from Utah's request. I understand his concern and the concern of people in both parties both sides of the aisle here in the
Senate to
Speaker 14 (lower-pitched voice): take action on this infant formula challenge that so many families are suffering through right now. The unfortunate part about this proposal is this will put babies at risk in ways that we don't
even
Speaker 14 (lower-pitched voice): fully understand right now. There's bipartisan concern, and the evidence for that is the action of committees, bipartisan work in several committees, including
Speaker 15: the Agriculture Committee as well as the Health Education Labor Pensions Committee, bipartisan work
Speaker 14 (lower-pitched voice): to meet this crisis. And the focus of that work has been to get formula on shelves as soon as possible.
Madam
Speaker 14 (lower-pitched voice): President,
Speaker 16 (lower-pitched voice): it's important to remember how our nation's formula crisis began. Abbott's recall, the manufacturer, the recall and the closure came after as many as nine infants died from contaminated formula. That's how this started, contaminated formula. Now we can and we should get to the bottom of the abject failures that led to contaminated formula hitting the shelves.
Speaker 16 (lower-pitched voice): I've been working on this for months, many months before this crisis came to a head. But we can't forget our top priority here when it comes to protecting infants. We've got to keep our nation's most vulnerable, these infants, safe. And it's pretty clear that the Food and Drug Administration bears responsibility for dropping the ball in so many ways, in terms of inspections,
But
Speaker 16 (lower-pitched voice): still, even despite that failure, the FDA standards are the best in the world.
And as I
Speaker 16 (lower-pitched voice): mentioned, the Agriculture and Health Committee has already done bipartisan work. And I think when you look at the—you saw the hearings that took place, especially in the Health Education Labor Pensions Committee—bipartisan condemnation.
of
Speaker 16 (lower-pitched voice): the Food and Drug Administration. Bipartisan calls for accountability at the Food and Drug Administration. And they should be hit very hard in terms of the accountability that should be imposed and must be imposed on the FDA. Unfortunately, this bill will completely disregard the FDA's standards for safety, which would put our children
at risk.
I'd also
Speaker 16 (lower-pitched voice): mention the HELP Committee's work marking up a bill last week, an FDA bill, amendments allowing importation during a shortage with appropriate guardrails to ensure formula is safe for our nation's infants. These bipartisan amendments represent a more appropriate path forward than this approach
today to
Speaker 16 (lower-pitched voice): limit the FDA's ability to protect our infants.
Now is
Speaker 16 (lower-pitched voice): not the time to completely abandon safety standards. We need to do everything we can to get formula back on shelves, but we can't compromise safety at any cost. Here's just some examples. Go to the FDA's website under the Food and Drug Administration Center for Food Safety and Applied Nutrition. Here's just a few examples from their database. July 2016, four-week-old baby in the U.S. was fed a stage one infant
Speaker 16 (lower-pitched voice): Milk product approved in nearly all the countries described in the senator's bill, but not in the U.S. After consuming that formula, the baby experienced diarrhea, fever, vomiting, and lethargy. The baby ended up in an emergency room where he was diagnosed with a salmonella infection. Second example, January 2017, one-month-old baby, similarly poisoned by a product approved by the countries in this bill, but not legally marketed in the U.S., and that baby began vomiting.
Speaker 16 (lower-pitched voice): January 2019, a five-month-old began experiencing upper abdominal pain, diarrhea, after consuming another such product. That's just a small example. These concerns are why the American Academy of Pediatrics for years has warned against importing formula from Europe.
Speaker 16 (lower-pitched voice): The Academy has published articles highlighting the dangers of buying imported baby formulas and advising against doing so. So despite all this, the Senator and others want to go forward with this bill. Here's the good news, the only good news in the short run. Here's the good news. We don't have to compromise safety standards to increase the supply. We already know.
that
Speaker 16 (lower-pitched voice): the administration's Operation Fly formula is bringing formula into the United States at a pretty rapid clip. Thirty-two flights, 19 million 8-ounce bottle equivalents of formula. That's not the end of it. The FDA right now is using enforcement discretion to allow the importation of additional select formula
Speaker 16 (lower-pitched voice): through normal distribution channels, bolstering the domestic supply of safe and nutritious formula by over 220 million 8-ounce bottle equivalents. Add the two of them together, you have almost 240 million bottles
Speaker 16 (lower-pitched voice): that are going to be, many of which have already been imported safely. The administration is also taking other steps to increase formula production domestically by invoking the Defense Production Act to prioritize critical ingredients and manufacturing supplies for infant formula production. So steps are being taken, but we cannot, when we're invoking the powers
of
Speaker 16 (lower-pitched voice): the executive branch or enacting legislation. We cannot compromise on safety. We have to have the highest safety standards in the world, which we do, and we've got to make
Speaker 14 (lower-pitched voice): sure that we adhere to those safety standards. So I object. Mr. President. The objection is heard.
Senator from Utah.
Mr. President, I
Speaker 12 (lower-pitched voice): appreciate the insights, the always thoughtful counsel of my distinguished friend and colleague, the senator from Pennsylvania. I always enjoy working with him. He's a voice of reason and a delight to work with. I do feel
Speaker 8: compelled to respond to a few of his points. Now, yes, it's true. There are ambitious plans to
Speaker 2: fly formula over. They use the Defense Production Act to do that, to have government to act.
Speaker 2: And the ambitious plans that he describes have yet to materialize. What we have to look at is the bottles that are available now, that have been flown over now, that are here now as a result of that program, it's
Speaker 4: about 13 million bottles. You know what
Speaker 8: the average daily consumption of formula is in America? Nine million. So this buys us a day and a half of formula, a day and a half, and it's still not plugging the problem. So that's
Speaker 1: not a solution.
As
Speaker 1: to the objection related to the FDA regs, he points to the safety concerns and highlights a few adverse incident reports, not necessarily
Speaker 2: linked to the formula itself, but things that people experienced as they were switching formulas. A lot of the symptoms that he described, all of them in fact, as I understand, including lethargy, diarrhea, and some of those have been linked.
to
Speaker 2: babies switching formula. So yes, when a baby switches formula, whether it's from one American brand to another or from an American brand to a European brand,
Speaker 4: it's not uncommon during this transition period for babies to react that way. Now, I wish, we wish, that it weren't necessary for them to switch to begin with. This was unnecessary to
Speaker 2: make them switch. And in fact, another point that I need to refute that he made at the outset about formula being responsible for the contamination, for a food-borne illness, it was in
fact not
the
Speaker 2: formula itself that caused that. In fact, an FDA investigation revealed that it wasn't the formula. It was a source of bottled water that had itself been contaminated. And it was that bottled water that the parents were mixing with the formula that turned out to be contaminated, by no fault of their own, but also by no fault of the manufacturer. So we gotta keep straight exactly what happened
Speaker 4: here and what didn't
happen.
Speaker 4: Finally, with regard to the safety risks, I understand this, and it's important that we be safe in doing this. We have to remember these are countries from which we currently import pharmaceutical products because we trust that their equivalent of the FDA is safe
Speaker 2: and is effective. So
if we don't
Speaker 2: trust them with respect to baby formula, I would submit that we should...
Speaker 2: trust them elsewhere. But in fact, we can trust them in these areas. None of those adverse incident reports he reported to, to my knowledge, have been linked to a defect or a contamination in the formula itself. Finally, it's important to remember that we have a massive health
Speaker 1: crisis
faced by these babies
Speaker 1: who are unable to get formula, children being hospitalized because they're dehydrated. These can have lasting consequences. They're occurring
Speaker 2: at a time when When the baby's brain development
Speaker 2: is on a very critical timeline. You don't want to interrupt that, you don't want a supply chain disruption to lead to a disruption in the baby's developmental growth. So it's unfortunate that my friend, a distinguished colleague, the senator from Pennsylvania,
Speaker 2: has
Speaker 3: objected to this very reasonable rational sensible response that lifts the government's impediments.
Speaker 4: I wish this were not the case because this would deliver meaningful reform. Unlike the 13 million bottles, the day and a half worth of formula that's been brought
Speaker 2: over to date through the Defense Production Act efforts that he described, this would actually solve the problem and it would solve it for at least six months long
Speaker 8: enough for our domestic production capabilities to resume.
Speaker 8: So it's unfortunate. I wish that were not the case, but I tell you what, in the spirit of comedy and
Speaker 3: compromise, I'll modify my request. Again, the Formula Act would have included these three legs, a regulatory component, lifting the regulatory restrictions, an import tariff restriction, and also lifting some restrictions in the WIC program.
And
Speaker 3: so I'm gonna counteroffer with another amendment that would remove the waiver of the
Speaker 2: FDA regulations for the imported formula. That, after all, is the concern he expressed, and so that should allow us to deal with it. It would keep the tariff and the WIC waivers from the Formula Act intact, and therefore shouldn't raise any concerns not addressed by my friend and distinguished colleague.
Speaker 8: And so, Mr. President,
Speaker 11: as if in legislative session I ask unanimous consent that the Senate proceed to the immediate consideration
of
Speaker 11: Calendar number 372 S-4261, further I ask that the lease substitute amendment at the desk be considered and agreed to,
Speaker 12 (lower-pitched voice): that the bill as amended be considered read a third time and passed, and that the motions to reconsider be considered made and laid upon the
Speaker 17: table. Is there objection?
Mr.
Speaker 14 (lower-pitched voice): President?
Speaker 17: Senator from Pennsylvania.
Mr.
Speaker 14 (lower-pitched voice): President, I object. Let me walk through why. My friend from Utah,
in the
Speaker 14 (lower-pitched voice): spirit to try to work something out here, is offering
a
Speaker 14 (lower-pitched voice): counter-proposal. The problem that I have with this is the amendment—now we're talking about the Department of Agriculture, which plays a role here, and
I'll get to
Speaker 14 (lower-pitched voice): that in a moment—but in this case, the amendment would direct this agency, the Department of Agriculture, to allow formula to be included in the Women, Infants, and Children's Nutrition Program
Speaker 14 (lower-pitched voice): that does not meet USDA standards. So now we
have a
Speaker 14 (lower-pitched voice): concern that I initially raised about FDA standards. Now we have USDA standards for safety and nutritional adequacy. I'd also add that this amendment is unnecessary because of action that was taken by the leaders of the Committee on Agriculture and Nutrition and Forestry. That committee,
passed
Speaker 14 (lower-pitched voice): a bipartisan bill, the Access to Baby Formula Act, that the president just signed into law. This already provides the agency, the United States Department of Agriculture, with the discretion it needs to expand the products available
to
Speaker 16 (lower-pitched voice): WIC parents and babies. Right now, that's the law. While also continuing to meet
Speaker 14 (lower-pitched voice): those high nutritional needs
Speaker 14 (lower-pitched voice): So again, the concern here are standards, safety standards,
Speaker 19: for those infants. The objection is
Speaker 12 (lower-pitched voice): heard. Mr. President. Senator from Utah. Mr. President, I find this too unfortunate. I wish we could
Speaker 9: adopt all three of these reforms. Again, we've got regulatory reform, an import tax reform, and a WIC reform.
He's
Speaker 9: now expressed objections to the regulatory reform and the WIC reform. So in
Speaker 8: the spirit of comedy and cooperation and compromise, I'd like to modify again.
Speaker 2: And I'll take out the WIC restriction, the WIC component of the bill, leaving only the tariff waiver. That at least would remove some of this protectionist problem that we've got
Speaker 4: in place that's currently prohibiting people from being able to import this stuff.
Speaker 4: leaving it available really only to wealthy, well-connected parents who know how to find the stuff and can pay
the
Speaker 12 (lower-pitched voice): higher price for it. This would at least allow people to buy it in stores if we could lift that restriction and do so in larger
Speaker 11: quantities while adhering to the labeling and other regulatory requirements. And so, Mr. President, as if in legislative session, I ask unanimous consent that the Senate proceed
to the
Speaker 11: immediate consideration of calendar number 372S4261. And further, I ask that the Lee substitute
Speaker 5: amendment
Speaker 5: at the desk be considered and agreed to; that the bill as amended be considered read a third time and passed; and that the motion to reconsider be considered made and laid upon the
Speaker 20: table. Is there objection?
Speaker 14 (lower-pitched voice): Mr. President? Senator Pennsylvania. I object. In this case, on a much more limited ground, here's the reason. The senator from Utah is trying to work something out here, and we appreciate that. The Democratic side has not had the opportunity
yet to review
Speaker 14 (lower-pitched voice): this amendment.
Speaker 14 (lower-pitched voice): So we would seek, in the interest of comedy, more time to review it. On that basis, I object. - The objection is heard.
Speaker 9: - Mr.
Speaker 14 (lower-pitched voice): President. - Senator
Speaker 1: from Utah. - I find it most unfortunate that as American babies are starving and are literally being admitted into hospitals for dehydration and malnutrition because of a government-created problem, we can't get to a solution here. I'm determined to find one, and I'm determined not to take no for an answer. We've got to get to yes on that. And so to that end,
Speaker 1: I'd like to modify my last request, shorten it down from 180 days, a six-month suspension, down to a 90, or down from 180 days to a 90-day suspension. This is the exact timeframe that mirrors the Biden administration's proposed time window for gas tax alleviation. Now, the president has raised this, has asked us to act on that immediately.
Speaker 1: I happen to think baby formula is a whole lot more important and urgent than gasoline.
So we
Speaker 1: can at least do this. And so I'm going to modify my request to move it down to just 90 days. We should be able to do that for 90 days. I'm certain that we can. And so, Mr. President, as if in legislative session, I ask unanimous consent that the Senate
proceed to
Speaker 1: the immediate consideration of calendar number
Speaker 11: 372
Speaker 5: S4261, further that the lease substitute amendment at the desk be considered.
Speaker 5: and agreed to, that the bill as amended be considered red a third time and passed, and that the motion to reconsider be considered made and laid upon the table.
Is there
Speaker 14 (lower-pitched voice): objection? Mr. President? Senator Pennsylvania. I object, and for the same narrow reason, that is that the Democratic side has not had the opportunity to review this amendment. We will do that on both this amendment and the prior amendment, and
see where we
Speaker 14 (lower-pitched voice): are. On that basis, I object. But I also add, for the record,
on the
The
Speaker 14 (lower-pitched voice): debate overall,
I think
Speaker 14 (lower-pitched voice): my friend is expressing a real concern that both sides have. It's not as if we just arrived here
today to
Speaker 14 (lower-pitched voice): start talking about this issue. As I said, for months now, the Health, Education, Labor and Pensions Committee, in a bipartisan way,
and the
Speaker 14 (lower-pitched voice): Committee on Agriculture and Nutrition, in a bipartisan way, has been working on these issues.
And
Speaker 14 (lower-pitched voice): so to suggest that somehow the debate just started today and neither side is doing enough, I think, is not accurate. Both sides are concerned about this. Both houses, both parties,
Speaker 16 (lower-pitched voice): very concerned about
it. And
Speaker 16 (lower-pitched voice): it's a real crisis. The FDA should be held accountable. Should, as I said earlier, be hit hard for
Speaker 14 (lower-pitched voice): this. But we can't compromise safety standards. And that's the reason for my objection.
The
Speaker 14 (lower-pitched voice): objection is
Speaker 23: heard, Senator from Utah.
Speaker 22: Mr. President, I appreciate the
Speaker 12 (lower-pitched voice): thoughts expressed by my friend and distinguished colleague, the Senator from Pennsylvania. I share this concern, this desire to see this worked out and worked out on a bipartisan basis. I think it is
Speaker 5: important. It is true that people have been working on it, they've been working on it now for
Speaker 1: the
a
Speaker 1: month and a half,
and yet
Speaker 1: nothing has happened. Now, I understand Rome wasn't built in a day. Significant legislative reforms are not usually
Speaker 12 (lower-pitched voice): enacted very quickly. Well, they are in some places, and we're experiencing some of that this week. That's a different issue altogether. But
Speaker 1: I understand that it takes time on many
occasions.
to
Speaker 1: develop a legislative solution. This is not one of those issues. This is just not that complicated. So I appreciate the fact
Speaker 2: that people are considering it. I appreciate the fact that my friend and colleague, the senator from Pennsylvania, is willing to try to clear this on the Democratic side. And I hope and expect that one of the four alternatives that I propose today, each in the spirit of comedy and compromise, something that should be acceptable to both political parties, has
got to get there.
There
Speaker 2: are issues on which
Speaker 9: we're always going to struggle to find a solution. This one isn't hard. We can do this. We can
fix
Speaker 2: this. American babies are going hungry because of mismanagement within our country. And yeah, I share your belief that we've got to hold the FDA accountable, but I feel like we're in the same position as the unarmed English Bobby with the FDA lately.
The
Speaker 2: unarmed English Bobby, who, being unarmed upon seeing the commission of a crime, shouts in his charming British accent, "Stop,
Speaker 4: or I will yell, 'Stop, again.'" We need to actually do something to force this issue, because people are going hungry. Babies are going hungry, and there are dire, long-lasting consequences. I hope and expect that we will solve this before the end of the week. This issue is not going away, and neither am I. Thank you, Mr. President.